Opera Guild of Southern Arizona records, 1958-1995
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Opera Guild of Southern Arizona records, 1958-1995
MS 321
Opera Guild of Southern Arizona Board of Directors
The bulk of the Opera Guild of Southern Arizona records pertains to the its annual activities, especially promotional, educational and fund-raising events. Monthly bulletins, scrapbooks and yearbooks document the many activities of the guild: opera previews, luncheons, dinners, sponsorship of opera students, scholarships, loans and grants, underwriting of annual Metropolitan and San Francisco opera auditions, aid to groups producing opera, and sponsorship of free matinees for school students.
7 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None.
Historical Note
The Opera Guild of Southern Arizona was conceived in 1957 by Ruth Booth who moved to Arizona that year. Finding no musical organizations dedicated to the promotion and expansion of opera in the area, Ms. Booth obtained the support of the Metropolitan Opera Guild in New York in her efforts to form a guild in Tucson. The charter meeting was held on April 13, 1958, with the stated aim of stimulating interest in and advancing the appreciation of opera as well as encouraging participation and bringing opera performances to audiences of all ages in Southern Arizona. The Opera Guild corporate in 1960 and continues its annual sponsorship of Metropolitan and San Francisco opera company auditions, student matinees, and a variety of fund-raising events intended to support community opera in Tucson. The Guild holds four to six regular board meetings annually.
Organization
Since the Opera Guild follows a fiscal and opera year calendar which runs from May through April, records which were originally arranged according to this fiscal pattern were retained in that order. Other records are arranged in calendar year order.
This collection is organized into six series:
I. Board records, 1958-1991
II. Bulletins and Yearbooks, 1958-1994
III. Correspondence, 1957-1995
IV. Sponsored Events, 1958-1994
V. Scrapbooks, 1958-1994
VI. Opera Auditions Audio Tapes, 1978-1981
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the Opera Guild of Southern Arizona records pertains to the its annual activities, especially promotional, educational and fund-raising events. Monthly bulletins, scrapbooks and yearbooks document the many activities of the guild: opera previews, luncheons, dinners, sponsorship of opera students, scholarships, loans and grants, underwriting of annual Metropolitan and San Francisco opera auditions, aid to groups producing opera, and sponsorship of free matinees for school students.
News clippings and photographs also document these varied activities. Organizational records include board minutes, financial statements, and a history of the guild's development. Additional materials are expected in the future.
Access Terms
Booth, Ruth
Opera Guild of Southern Arizona
Opera -- Arizona
Music -- Arizona -- Tucson -- 20th Century
Music -- Societies, etc.
Tucson (Ariz.) -- History
Correspondence
Photographs
Separated Material
Approximately 2.5 linear feet of records were not retained. These consisted primarily of duplicate materials such as board minutes and monthly bulletins. In addition, the contents of photo albums, scrapbooks and notebooks were moved to file folders.
Container List
- Series I: Board Records, 1958-1991
  - Guild organization history. No Dates (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Oraganizational meetings. No Dates (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Historical. No Dates (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Articles of incorporation. No Dates (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Guidelines. No Dates (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Constitution and By-laws. No Dates (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Board and committee members. No Dates (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Board and committee minutes. 1958-1991 (Box 1, Folder 8-14)
  - Board minutes. 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Greene bequest and investment. No Dates (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Assistance fund. No Dates (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Barnes Loan Fund. No Dates (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ruiz donation, University of Arizona School of Music. No Dates (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Booth Scholarship. No Dates (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Booth Scholarship, Humphrey correspondence. No Dates (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Financial statements. 1961-1992 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Insurance. No Dates (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Historian's report. No Dates (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Charter members. No Dates (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Membership. No Dates (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Membership development. No Dates (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Helpers. No Dates (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Series II: Bulletins and Yearbooks, 1958-1994
  - Bulletins. 1958-1994 (Box 3, Folder 4-11)
  - Yearbooks. 1968-1994 (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
- Series III: Correspondence, 1957-1995
  - Correspondence. 1957-1985 (Box 4, Folder 1-27)
  - Correspondence. 1985-1995 (Box 5, Folder 1-11)
- Series IV: Sponsored Events, 1958-1994
  - Publicity materials. No Dates (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Student singers, Janice Felty. No Dates (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Student singers, Jerry Howell. No Dates (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Student singers, Joseph Pinedo. No Dates (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Opera Dinner. 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 16-17)
  - Opera dinner. 1960-1977 (Box 6, Folder 1-10)
  - Tucson Civic Chorus. 1959 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Preview, Othello. 1964 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Preview, Tales of Hoffman. 1967 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Preview, Don Giovanni. 1972 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - University of Arizona Artist Series, La Boheme. 1964 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Mad Hatters Brunch. 1966 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Boris Gudunov. 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Luncheon. 1975 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - University of Arizona School of Music Benefit. 1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Luncheon, Holiday in Italy. 1980 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Goldovsky Concert. 1981 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Tea. 1985 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Western Opera Theater. 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Ditty Bags. 1968-1971 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Materials. 1962-1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Old Pueblo Experiential Repertory Adventure. 1987-1990 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Tours. 1978-1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities Proposal. 1979 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Student Matinees. 1968-1980 (Box 7, Folder 9-16)
  - Student Matinees. 1980-1994 (Box 8, Folder 1-9)
  - Student Matinee "Thank You" letters. No Dates (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Alliance of Arizona Opera Guilds. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Regional Auditions History. 1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Arizona Opera Auditions. 1962-1988 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Arizona Opera Auditions Fund. 1961-1970 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Arizona Opera Auditions Fund. 1961-1970 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Audition Winners: New York & San Francisco. 1957-1973 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Metropolitan Opera Auditions. 1958-1978 (Box 9, Folder 5-11)
  - Metropolitan Opera Auditions. 1978-1987 (Box 10, Folder 1-6)
  - San Francisco Opera Auditions: Merola. 1965-1987 (Box 10, Folder 7-12)
  - Merola Opera-Guild Sponsorship of David Majors. 1980 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Series V: Scrapbooks, 1958-1994
  - Scrapbooks. 1958-1966 (Box 10, Folder 14-21)
  - Scrapbooks. 1966-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1-11)
  - Scrapbooks. 1981-January 1992 (Box 12, Folder 1-5)
  - Scrapbooks. February 1992-May 1994 (Box 13, Folder 1-4)
- Series VI: Opera Auditions Audio Tapes, 1978-1981
  - San Francisco Opera Auditions (7" reels). 1980 (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Metropolitan Opera Auditions (7" reels). 1981 (Box 14, Folder 3-6)
  - AIDA Preview (audio cassettes). No Dates (Box 14, Folder 7-8)
  - Metropolitan Opera Auditions (10.5" reels). 1978 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Metropolitan Opera Auditions (10.5" reels). 1979 (Box 15, Folder 2-4)